Gokul G.K

Software Development Engineer - 3 @ Walmart

Banglore, Karnataka, +91 9544406978

gokulgk1200@gmail.com, LinkedIn

Proficient in Java, spring boot, Microservices, AWS cloud, Azure cosmos, Apache Kafka, Jax-Rs and IoT technologies, team management, designing, and solutioning. Worked on Kubernetes, Angular, Electron, Jenkins, Docker, Jmeter, Node-red, OSGi, and google guice.

Currently working on Digital messaging platform for walmart, Solving complex real-world problems through technology and innovation.

Experience

Walmart - Banglore (July 2019 - July 2022)

Software Engineer - 3 July 2022 - Present

Project: Digital messaging platform: Messaging service for Health and wellness department.

Tech stack: Microservice, Java, Walmart Cloud, Azure Cosmos, Apache Kafka, Kubernetes, Splunk, Prometheus, Graffana and Jenkins

Thermofisher Scientific - Banglore (July 2019 - July 2022)

Software Engineer -2 April 2021 - July - 2022

Project: Lab edge - Edge Computing with the actual gateway device.

Responsibilities Involves

- Solutioning and review of feature tickets and design documents. ,Resolving team dependencies and blockers.
- Design and development of cloud microservice with AWS and edge computing distributed system using Java..

Tech stack: Microservice, Java, AWS, Cloud application, Jax-Rs, google guice, REST, H2, Edge application, DDD, Eclipse Kura framework, AWS -SDK, OSGi, Docker, Jenkins, Jfrog, IoT

Software Engineer -1 July 2019 - April 2021

Project: Connect Transfer - Desktop application with IoT capabilities

Responsibilities Involves

- Backend development and unit testing with Java and spring boot, Frontend development using angular and electron and IoT development using nodered and AWS IoT
- API automation using JMeter and Manual testing

Tech stack: Java, Spring boot, Nodered, REST, PostgreSQL, AWS IOT, Angular, Electron, Jmeter, Jenkins, IoT

Education

B.Tech in E.C.E - National Institute of Technology, Calicut

June 2015 - April - 2019

Passed with first class